Dr Jon G. C. Kragskow

Department of Chemistry, University of Bath, UK www.kragskow.dev jgck20@bath.ac.uk

A fast and enthusiastic learner with a strong background in computational and theoretical chemistry, particularly as applied to magnetic and spectroscopic properties of transition metal and lanthanide systems. Passionate about building well-documented and open-source tools which make research easier, clearer, and more approachable. Committed to education, particularly through the creation of modern and interactive digital resources.

EMPLOYMENT

UNIVERSITY OF BATH Bath, UK

Post-Doctoral Research Associate

January 2023-Ongoing

- EPSRC funded position in computational chemistry supervised by Dr Elizaveta Suturina.
- Implemented new computational tools for routine simulation and analysis of paramagnetic NMR spectra in both biological and chemical systems.
- Calculated and simulated of magnetic properties of exchange-coupled transition metal complexes using *ab initio* methods and spin-Hamiltonian modelling.
- Participation in academic exchange visits to Florence, Italy (protein NMR experiments) and Bordeaux, France (proton NMR and magnetochemistry experiments).
- Tutor in first year physical chemistry, and demonstrator/contributor for second year computational chemistry lab experiments.

THE UNIVERSITY OF MANCHESTER

Manchester, UK

Post-Doctoral Research Associate

April 2022-October 2022

- ERC funded position in computational chemistry supervised by Prof. Nicholas Chilton.
- Modelled magnetic behaviour of molecular nanomagnets using ab initio quantum chemistry, particularly in the solid-state.
- Led development of magnetochemistry software such as *ccfit2*, a python package for fitting experimental magnetic data.
- Trained of group members in python and Fortran software development and best practices for code deployment and version control through code-review sessions, documentation, and workshops.
- Maintained and architected group subversion and git code repositories and created automated pipelines for code documentation and release.

EDUCATION

THE UNIVERSITY OF MANCHESTER

Manchester, UK

PhD in Chemistry Associate - "Chemical Control of Spin-Phonon Coupling"

September 2018-April 2022

- PhD position in group of Prof. Nicholas Chilton funded by EPSRC studentship and University of Manchester President's Doctoral Scholarship.
- Calculated spin-phonon coupling (SPC) in lanthanide coordination complexes using *ab initio* quantum chemistry and spin-Hamiltonian approaches.
- Developed novel methodologies and software for the simulation of SPC-derived properties such as magnetic relaxation rates and magnetic field dependent infrared spectroscopy data.
- Collaborations with experimental groups in Xi'an Jiaotong University (China), the National High Magnetic Field lab (Florida, United States), and University of Copenhagen (Denmark).
- Instructed 2nd year undergraduates in MATLAB programming, marked lab scripts and carried out individual student assessment interviews. Overhauled course material and adapted course for distance learning during COVID-19.

THE UNIVERSITY OF MANCHESTER

Manchester, UK

Daguas Classification First

MChem in Chemistry

September 2014-June 2018

- Degree Classification: First Class
- Outstanding Academic Achievement Award for top 0.5% of graduating students in Faculty of Science and Engineering.

COMPUTATIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

Beginner JavaScript, Docker, flask, Apache, C++

Intermediate HTML, CSS, Qt, Bash

Experienced Python, Fortran90, Git, Subversion, make, MATLAB, GitLab CI/CD

Open-Source Software Development

ccfit2 A python package for working with experimental magnetometry data. Users can input a magnetometer

output file and obtain a fitted plot of their data using a single command and an interactive interface. Thanks to its modular design and rich documentation, ccfit2 can be included in users own python code with ease.

Waveplot An online wavefunction viewer which demonstrates simple concepts in quantum chemistry. Waveplot is

built with students in mind and features the model quantum systems they encounter in introductory quantum chemistry. Students can manipulate input variables, plots, and download raw data to use in their

own work.

AtomAccess A python package which quantifies steric hindrance at chemical centres using raytracing. I wrote

AtomAccess to be fast and user-friendly through either its simple web-interface, or through command-line

and scripting.

Tau A C++/Fortan90 program for the simulation of magnetic relaxation rates. Tau uses *ab initio* spin-phonon

coupling data to accurately simulate magnetic relaxation under a range of conditions using a semi-classical

master equation.

FIRMS_SIM A Fortran90 program for the simulation of magnetic field dependent infrared spectroscopy. FIRMS_SIM

uses ab initio spin-phonon coupling data to simulate the infrared spectra of molecules in varying magnetic

fields.

Technical Skills

Quantum Chemistry High-level knowledge of computational and quantum chemistry methods (HF, DFT, CASSCF, CASPT2), and

experience in using established programs (Gaussian, OpenMOLCAS, ORCA).

Magnetism Experienced in analysis and workup of experimental magnetometry data (AC susceptibility, DC Decay,

magnetisation and susceptibility). Expert knowledge of phenomenological and spin-Hamiltonian modelling

techniques.

HPC Proficient HPC user, familiar with a variety of schedulers and systems of differing scale (AWS, Azure, local

clusters, Tier-2 HPC). Experience in creating and maintaining group-level clusters/systems.

FUNDING SECURED

2023	British Council -	- Exchange program	between	Universities o	f Bath and	Bordeaux (£7k)
------	-------------------	--------------------	---------	----------------	------------	------------	-----	---

2022 Royal Society of Chemistry –Researcher Mobility Grant (£500)

2017 Royal Society of Chemistry - Undergraduate Summer Research Bursary (£1.5k)

2016 The University of Manchester - Undergraduate Departmental Research Bursary (£1k)

AWARDS

2021	The University	of Manchester -	 Outstanding Postgraduate 	Academic Achievement Award
------	----------------	-----------------	--	----------------------------

The University of Manchester – President's Doctoral Scholarship

2018 The University of Manchester – Outstanding Undergraduate Academic Achievement Award

PUBLICATIONS

- 13. G. K. Gransbury, S. C. Corner, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, P. Evans, H. Yeung, W. J. A. Blackmore, G. F. S. Whitehead, I. J. Vitorica-Yrezabal, Meagan S. Oakley, N. F. Chilton and D. P. Mills, *J. Am. Chem. Soc.*, 2023, **145**, 41, 22814–22825
- 12. R. Nabi, J. K. Staab, A. Mattioni, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, D. Reta, J. M. Skelton and N. F. Chilton, *J. Am. Chem. Soc.*, 2023, **145**, 45, 24558–24567

- 11. B. Alnami, J. G. C. Kragskow, J. K. Staab, J. M. Skelton and N. F. Chilton, J. Am. Chem. Soc., 2023, 145, 25, 13632-13639
- 10. J. G. C. Kragskow, A. Mattioni, J. K. Staab, D. Reta, J. M. Skelton and N. F. Chilton, Chem. Soc. Rev., 2023, 52, 4567
- 9. W J. A. Blackmore, G. K. Gransbury, P. Evans, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, D. P. Mills, N. F. Chilton, *Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys.*, 2023, **25**, 16735-16744
- 8. K. R. McClain, H. Kwon, K. Chakarawet, R. Nabi, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, N. F. Chilton, R. D. Britt, J. R. Long and B. G. Harvey, *J. Am. Chem. Soc.*, 2023, **145**, 8996–9002
- 7. **J. G. C. Kragskow**, J. Marbey, C. D. Buch, J. Nehrkorn, M. Ozerov, S. Piligkos, S. Hill and N. F. Chilton, *Nat. Commun.*, 2022, **13**, 825
- 6. C. A. Gould, K. R. McClain, D. Reta, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, D. A. Marchiori, E. Lachman, E.-S. Choi, J. G. Analytis, R. D. Britt, N. F. Chilton, B. G. Harvey and J. R. Long, *Science*, 2022, **375**, 198-202
- 5. D. Reta, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, N. F. Chilton, J. Am. Chem. Soc., 2021, **143**, 5943–5950
- 4. K.-X. Yu, J. G. C. Kragskow, Y.-S. Ding, Y.-Q. Zhai, D. Reta, N. F. Chilton, Y.-Z. Zheng, *Chem*, 2020, 6, 1–17
- 3. C. A. P. Goodwin, B. L. L. Réant, G. F. Vettese, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, M. J. Giansiracusa, I. M. Dimucci, K. M. Lancaster, D. P. Mills, S. Sproules, *Inorg. Chem.*, 2020, **59**, 7571–7583
- 2. H. M. Nicholas, C. A. P. Goodwin, J. G. C. Kragskow, S. J. Lockyer, D. P. Mills, *Molecules*, 2018, 23, 1138
- 1. C. A. P. Goodwin, B. L. L. Réant, **J. G. C. Kragskow**, I. M. DiMucci, K. M. Lancaster, D. P. Mills and S. Sproules, *Dalton Trans.*, 2018, 47, 10613–1062

PRESENTATIONS

Contributed Talks

- 2022 Ultrahard magnetism from mixed-valence dilanthanide complexes with metal-metal bonding
 - 7th European Conference on Molecular Magnetism, Rennes
- Vibronic coupling in a 4f qubit
 - American Physical Society March Meeting, Chicago
- 2021 Ab initio relaxation dynamics in Lanthanide Single Molecule Magnets
 - Department of Chemistry Postgraduate Symposium, The University of Manchester
- Vibronic coupling in a 4f qubit
 - 17th International Conference on Molecule Based Magnets Rising Star Symposium, The University of Manchester
- 2021 Enhancing Magnetic Hysteresis in Single-Molecule Magnets by Ligand Functionalization
 - Department of Chemistry Staff Symposium, The University of Manchester
- 2018 Understanding the Crystal Field of Metal Complexes
 - Midlands Computational Chemistry Conference, Nottingham Trent University

Posters

- 2024 Understanding the Electronic Structures of Transition Metal Complexes using Paramagnetic NMR Spectroscopy Spin Meeting 2024, The University of Manchester
- 2023 Understanding the Electronic Structures of Transition Metal Complexes using Paramagnetic NMR Spectroscopy
 19th European Magnetic Resonance Congress, Glasgow
- 2019 Ab initio Relaxation Dynamics of Dysprosium(III) Single Molecule Magnets
 - 7th European Conference on Molecular Magnetism, University of Florence
- 2019 Ab initio Relaxation Dynamics of Dysprosium(III) Single Molecule Magnets
 - CASTEP Users Meeting, University of Oxford
- Ab initio Relaxation Dynamics of Dysprosium(III) Single Molecule Magnets
 - Royal Society of Chemistry Theoretical Chemistry Group Graduate Meeting, University of Nottingham
- 2018 Understanding the Crystal Field of Metal Complexes
 - National Training School in Theoretical Chemistry Summer School, University of Oxford